All hail.
The King is a drama, history, war film directed by David Michôd.
England, 15th century.
Hal, a capricious prince who lives among the populace far from court, is forced by
circumstances to reluctantly accept the throne and become Henry V.
Hal, played by Timothée Chalamet.
Falstaff, played by Joel Edgerton.
William, played by Sean Harris.
Hotspur, played by Tom Glynn-Carney.
Catherine, played by Lily-Rose Depp.
Philippa, Queen of Denmark, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
The King is a 2019 epic historical drama film directed by David Michôd,
based on several plays from William Shakespeare's Henriad.
The screenplay was written by Michôd and Joel Edgerton, who both produced the
film with Brad Pitt, Dede Gardner, Jeremy Kleiner, and Liz Watts.
The King includes an ensemble cast led by Timothée Chalamet as the Prince of Wales and later King Henry V of
England, alongside Edgerton, Sean Harris, Lily-Rose Depp, Robert Pattinson, and Ben Mendelsohn.
The film focuses on the rise of Henry V as king after his father dies as he also must navigate palace
politics, the war his father left behind, and the emotional strings of his past life.
The King premiered at the 76th Venice International Film Festival on 2 September
2019, and was released digitally via Netflix on 11 October 2019.
The film received favourable reviews from film critics but, despite being presented as an adaptation of Shakespeare's Henriad rather than as a
historical documentary film, was criticised by historians for historical inaccuracies and for deviating from the original plays.
The film explores themes of biography, based on true story, hundred
years' war, historical fiction, british history.
The tone is emotional.